<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://unscramblr.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://unscramblr.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-11-08T15:25:18+00:00</updated><id>https://unscramblr.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Vibhore Kumar</title><subtitle>Vibhore Kumar&apos;s personal website. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">GenAI Powered ETL Crew for Migrating Legacy ETL Pipelines</title><link href="https://unscramblr.github.io/genai/2024/11/04/etl-crew.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="GenAI Powered ETL Crew for Migrating Legacy ETL Pipelines"/><published>2024-11-04T21:01:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-04T21:01:00+00:00</updated><id>https://unscramblr.github.io/genai/2024/11/04/etl-crew</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://unscramblr.github.io/genai/2024/11/04/etl-crew.html"><![CDATA[<p>Migrating ETL pipelines from legacy systems to modern, cloud-based frameworks is a complex but critical task for many enterprises. Ensuring compatibility, migrating large amounts of data, and maintaining system reliability are all substantial challenges. To streamline this transition, we’ve introduced a team of Generative AI-powered agents called the ETL Crew—a smart, autonomous team comprised of three specialized AI agents: Owl Lead (tech lead), Owl Dev (developer), and Owl QA (quality assurance engineer). Built on the CrewAI framework, the ETL Crew offers an efficient, automated ETL migration solution that incorporates human oversight at key stages, blending the benefits of automation with the assurance of human validation.</p> <p>This AI-driven solution integrates with Jira for task management, GitHub for version control, Microsoft Teams for communication, and Langfuse for prompt management, debugging, and cost tracking. At the core of this solution is the end-to-end (E2E) testing phase, which validates the success of each migration, ensuring the migrated code performs as expected and identifying any issues before final deployment.</p> <h2 id="the-etl-crew-key-components-and-workflow">The ETL Crew: Key Components and Workflow</h2> <h3 id="step-1-task-creation-and-assignment">Step 1: Task Creation and Assignment</h3> <p>The migration process begins with a human setting up a Jira task that includes all the necessary details, such as pointers to the legacy code in GitHub and validation datasets. Once assigned to the Owl Lead in Jira, the ETL Crew’s workflow kicks off, streamlining the migration process.</p> <h3 id="step-2-owl-lead-takes-charge">Step 2: Owl Lead Takes Charge</h3> <p>The Owl Lead operates as a tech lead, empowered by CrewAI’s prompt management capabilities:</p> <ul> <li>Task Initialization and Analysis: Owl Lead moves the task to “In Progress” in Jira, acknowledges it in Microsoft Teams, and begins analyzing the task requirements using CrewAI’s natural language capabilities.</li> <li>Clarification Requests: If the task needs further details, Owl Lead communicates directly with the human task creator via Microsoft Teams or Jira comments to ensure clarity.</li> <li>Subtask Creation and Assignment: Once the task is clear, Owl Lead generates subtasks for Owl Dev and Owl QA in Jira and assigns specific responsibilities.</li> <li>Human-in-the-Loop Option 1: Before Owl Dev and Owl QA begin their tasks, a human can review and validate the subtasks created by Owl Lead, ensuring all instructions are clear and accurate for the AI agents.</li> </ul> <h3 id="step-3-owl-dev-in-action">Step 3: Owl Dev in Action</h3> <p>Owl Dev takes on the role of developer, translating and adapting the legacy code with CrewAI’s help:</p> <ul> <li>Code Analysis and Translation: Owl Dev retrieves the legacy ETL code from GitHub and uses CrewAI’s transformer-based models to adapt it to the target framework (e.g., Spark, AWS Glue).</li> <li>Automated Code Generation and Unit Testing: CrewAI enables Owl Dev to generate equivalent code for the target environment, along with unit tests to validate functionality.</li> <li>Commit and Pull Request: After generating the code, Owl Dev commits it to GitHub and raises a pull request, completing its part in the development process.</li> </ul> <h3 id="step-4-owl-qa-ensures-quality-with-critical-e2e-testing">Step 4: Owl QA Ensures Quality with Critical E2E Testing</h3> <p>Owl QA, the quality assurance agent, ensures the migration’s success through rigorous end-to-end (E2E) testing using the provided validation datasets—a critical step in the entire process:</p> <ul> <li>E2E Testing with Validation Datasets: Owl QA uses the validation datasets to run end-to-end tests on the migrated pipeline, ensuring it performs identically to the legacy system. This testing phase is essential as it verifies that the code has been correctly migrated, confirming accuracy and functionality.</li> <li>Error Detection and Notification: If errors are detected during E2E testing, Owl QA notifies Owl Dev, who then investigates and corrects the issues, committing changes as needed. This iterative feedback loop between Owl QA and Owl Dev guarantees that the final migration meets quality standards before progressing.</li> <li>Build and Test Execution: Using GitHub Actions or other CI/CD tools, CrewAI triggers a build, runs unit and E2E tests, and logs results. Owl QA also provides progress updates via Microsoft Teams, ensuring all stakeholders are informed.</li> </ul> <p>Importance of E2E Testing: The E2E testing step is crucial as it verifies that the migrated code performs as expected, preventing issues from reaching production. Through validation testing, any inconsistencies are identified early, minimizing risk and reinforcing confidence in the migration’s success.</p> <h3 id="step-5-final-review-and-task-completion">Step 5: Final Review and Task Completion</h3> <p>With successful E2E testing, the Owl Lead returns to review and complete the migration:</p> <ul> <li>Code Review: Owl Lead conducts a thorough code review, checking for compliance with coding standards and CrewAI’s best practices.</li> <li>Approval and Merge: Upon final approval, Owl Lead merges the pull request in GitHub and updates the Jira task status to “Done”. <ul> <li>Human-in-the-Loop Option 2: A human reviewer may be introduced here to review the pull request before final merge, providing additional assurance that the code meets all migration criteria and quality standards.</li> </ul> </li> <li>Task Closure: After the PR merge, CrewAI sends a final update in Microsoft Teams, providing stakeholders with a summary of the completed migration.</li> </ul> <h2 id="video-demo-see-the-etl-crew-in-action">Video Demo: See the ETL Crew in Action</h2> <p>The accompanying video demonstrates the ETL Crew handling a complete migration, from task setup through E2E testing and final code merge. You’ll see each agent in action, along with the critical role of human validation at specific points in the workflow.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-12 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <div style="position: relative; width: 100%; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;"> <figure> <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5Vb4oDTf8Gg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" width="auto" height="auto"/> </figure> </div> </div> </div> <figure> <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5Vb4oDTf8Gg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" width="100%" height="auto"/> </figure> <h2 id="benefits-of-the-crewai-powered-etl-crew">Benefits of the CrewAI-Powered ETL Crew</h2> <p>The CrewAI-powered ETL Crew offers transformative benefits, significantly enhancing the speed, cost-efficiency, and reliability of ETL migrations:</p> <ol> <li>Reduces Migration Time by up to 40%: The ETL Crew automates repetitive and time-consuming tasks, enabling swift transitions between development, testing, and review stages. This efficiency reduces the typical migration timeline by up to 40%, allowing organizations to realize the benefits of a modern ETL pipeline faster.</li> <li>Decreases Migration Costs by up to 25%: By leveraging generative AI for much of the heavy lifting, the ETL Crew reduces the need for extensive human resources and minimizes the operational costs associated with long migration projects. With Langfuse’s cost-tracking integration, teams can monitor and optimize resource use, achieving up to 25% cost savings.</li> <li>Mitigates Risk in Complex, Long-Running ETL Projects: The ETL Crew’s structured workflow and critical E2E testing stage ensure that each migration phase is verified for quality and functionality. This robust testing, combined with human validation checkpoints, reduces the risk of errors in production, making the ETL Crew a reliable solution for complex migration projects with high stakes. This combination of reduced time and cost, along with lowered project risk, makes the ETL Crew an ideal solution for organizations looking to modernize their ETL pipelines with confidence.</li> </ol> <h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2> <p>The GenAI-powered ETL Crew revolutionizes the ETL migration process, combining the efficiency of automation with the reliability of human validation. By reducing migration time by up to 40%, cutting costs by up to 25%, and minimizing risks associated with complex, long-running projects, the ETL Crew delivers a streamlined, cost-effective solution for migrating ETL pipelines to modern cloud frameworks. With robust E2E testing and human oversight at critical points, the ETL Crew ensures each migration meets the highest standards of quality and accuracy. This hybrid approach empowers organizations to confidently transition to scalable, cloud-native infrastructure, unlocking new opportunities for data-driven transformation.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="GenAI"/><category term="multi-agent"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[GenAI Powered ETL Crew for Migrating Legacy ETL Pipelines]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Should Enterprises Consider A Large Language Model Strategy?</title><link href="https://unscramblr.github.io/2023/05/19/should-enterprises-consider-a-large-language-model-strategy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Should Enterprises Consider A Large Language Model Strategy?"/><published>2023-05-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-05-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://unscramblr.github.io/2023/05/19/should-enterprises-consider-a-large-language-model-strategy</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://unscramblr.github.io/2023/05/19/should-enterprises-consider-a-large-language-model-strategy.html"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The rise of large language models presents a unique opportunity for executives at large enterprises to transform and automate large swaths of their businesses, enhance customer experiences and unlock valuable insights from vast amounts of data.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">At The Dawn Of Artificial General Intelligence: Balancing Abundance With Existential Safeguards</title><link href="https://unscramblr.github.io/2023/01/24/at-the-dawn-of-artificial-general-intelligence-balancing-abundance-with-existential-safeguards.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="At The Dawn Of Artificial General Intelligence: Balancing Abundance With Existential Safeguards"/><published>2023-01-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-01-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://unscramblr.github.io/2023/01/24/at-the-dawn-of-artificial-general-intelligence-balancing-abundance-with-existential-safeguards</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://unscramblr.github.io/2023/01/24/at-the-dawn-of-artificial-general-intelligence-balancing-abundance-with-existential-safeguards.html"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The journey toward AGI will undoubtedly challenge us, but with collaboration, foresight and wisdom, humanity can harness its immense potential for the greater good.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Digital Sidekicks Are Here. Is Your Organization Onboarding Them?</title><link href="https://unscramblr.github.io/2021/10/11/digital-sidekicks-are-here-is-your-organization-onboarding-them.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Digital Sidekicks Are Here. Is Your Organization Onboarding Them?"/><published>2021-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://unscramblr.github.io/2021/10/11/digital-sidekicks-are-here-is-your-organization-onboarding-them</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://unscramblr.github.io/2021/10/11/digital-sidekicks-are-here-is-your-organization-onboarding-them.html"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As seamless as the technology might have become, organizations will have to establish an onboarding framework for a successful rollout.]]></summary></entry></feed>